<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on CSS Group @ The Alan Turing Institute</title>
    <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on CSS Group @ The Alan Turing Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://turingcss.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A project</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project description stuff
People Person 1
Publications Emerging labour flow networks (2023)
Resources link to any code or external websites etc
Project code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic SDG Alignment and Budget Tagging</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/budget_tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/budget_tagging/</guid>
      <description>Project description The “budgeting for SDGs”–B4SDGs–paradigm seeks to coordinate the budgeting process of the fiscal cycle with the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) set by the United Nations. Integrating the goals into public financial management systems is crucial for an effective alignment of national development priorities with the objectives set in the 2030 Agenda. Within the dynamic process defined in the B4SDGs framework, the step of SDG budget tagging represents a precondition for subsequent budget diagnostics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Security Index</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/climate_security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/climate_security/</guid>
      <description>Project description Climate variability is widely impacting natural and human systems. One of the many impacts is its potential threat to human security. The role of climate variability as a possible cause of violent conflict has been coming to the forefront of public and scientific debates. In this so-called Climate Security Nexus, climate variability acts as a multidirectional threat multiplier, aggravating existing vulnerabilities of people and communities.
In this project, we collaborate with CGIAR Focus Climate Security to devise a quantitative framework to develop a Climate Security Index (CSI), for measuring and monitoring climate security vulnerability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting Fringe Behaviour in Companies</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/firms_fringe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/firms_fringe/</guid>
      <description>Project description Complicated company ownership structures are often set up to obfuscate the identification of beneficial owners. These strategies are considered to be on the fringe of legitimacy and legality, so detecting them is important to regulators and society in general. We combine economic theory, network analysis, and machine learning to unearth the patterns that such behaviours leave behind in large-scale administrative datasets. This allows us to identify clusters of companies that specialise in such strategies, and to formulate models about their potential adaptation to future legal reforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endogenous Production Networks</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/endogenous_production_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/endogenous_production_network/</guid>
      <description>Project description Production networks live at the heart of modern economies and global value chains. Shocks such as demand shifts, technological change, and the emergence (death) of new (old) industries generate responses that propagate across their linkages. Most analytic tools analyse some of these shocks by considering production networks to be exogenous, while others that try to explain their formation have limited real-world applicability. This project is developing models of how such networks emerge from the learning process of firms under uncertainty; without having perfect knowledge of the nature of technology (also known as production functions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Government and Media Behaviour</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/gov_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/gov_media/</guid>
      <description>Project description The relationship between government and media is often intricate, complicated, and highly dependent on institutional context. Emerging large-scale data such as news content and open government spending datasets provides us with new information to understand this relationship. In this project, we combine this type of information with machine learning and econometrics to disentangle the various nuances of how the media influences policymaking and how policymakers influence the media. The project identifies generates novel evidence that sheds new light on this problem, and that can be used to design better regulatory frameworks when aiming to safeguard democracy and free press.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing Market Dynamics</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/housing_market/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/housing_market/</guid>
      <description>Project description In major cities around the world, housing markets are in the eye of public opinion; not only because of their economic importance, but also due to the recent growth of inequality. The analysis of these complex systems demand tools that can handle large-scale data, heterogeneous agents and institutions, spatial features, agent-level economic behaviour and interaction, etc. This project develops models and tools to study various phenomena related to housing markets such as endogenous inequality, spatial impacts from changes in infrastructure, affordability, and ownership-rental flows, among others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Trade Modelling</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/int_trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/int_trade/</guid>
      <description>Project description International trade is a complex economic problem. New trade data and computational modelling techniques allow us to develop new types of models that account for nuances and dynamics that standard economic models cannot. Our models enable trade analysists and policymakers to gain deep insight into the potential outcomes of policies such as creating new trade agreements.
People Cosmina Dorobantu Nishanth Kumar Tuong M. Vu Ernesto Carrela Omar A. Guerrero Resources Online repository (upcoming)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labour Flow Networks</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/labour_flow_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/labour_flow_networks/</guid>
      <description>Project description We develop models explaining the movement of individuals within the labour market. Our models are highly granular and can exploit micro-data of different types (e.g. labour force surveys &amp;amp; administrative records) to emerge detailed large-scale patterns of job-to-job transitions from agent-level behaviour. Taken collectively, these job-to-job transitions constitute a labour flow network (LFN) where nodes contain pools of jobs with shared characteristics (e.g. they are within the same industry, geographical region, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Projects</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/various/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/various/</guid>
      <description>Project 1: Emerging age structures for ABMs Applications of agent-based models (ABMs) frequently incorporate the feature that an agent&amp;rsquo;s age impacts their decision-making (e.g. as regards risk aversion) and outcomes (e.g. susceptibility to disease). Thus, it is important that the ABM also accurately captures the age distribution of the population being modelled. However, it is often difficult to generate realistic age distributions using empirical survival probabilities, due to mis-matches between samples (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policy Priority Inference</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/ppi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/ppi/</guid>
      <description>Project description The Policy Priority Inference (PPI) research programme aims at modelling the causal link between government expenditure and policy outcomes while accounting for the multidimensionality and complexity of development. It employs computational methods to overcome the limitations of coarse-grained data on development indicators and public spending. Multidimensionality means that development occurs, simultaneously, in a variety of policy issues, for example, poverty, public health, education, air pollution, etc. An example of a multidimensional development international agenda is the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Technological Sophistication</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/tech_sophistication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/tech_sophistication/</guid>
      <description>Project description Technological sophistication drives economic growth and diversification. We develop methods to quantify the degree of sophistication of entire industries and to understand how various inputs come together in a production process to generate novel outputs. Our tools build on recent advances in information theory and machine learning, and provide policymakers with insights to make strategic decisions when promoting investments in specific industries.
People Hardik Rajpal Tuong M. Vu Omar A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skill Interaction and Complexity</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/skills_complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/skills_complexity/</guid>
      <description>Project description An understanding of the ways skills interact with each other to influence career trajectories of individuals, and the productivity of occupations is key to developing labour market policies (e.g. upskilling programs). Leveraging rich microdata covering multiple countries and novel techniques developed within the computational social science group, this project explores how workplace skills interact with each other to impact outcomes at the micro- and macro-level, as well as their evolution through the labour market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skill Sorting and Productivity</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/skill_sorting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/skill_sorting/</guid>
      <description>Project description We develop models of endogenous technology which centre skill-based worker sorting in its operation. These tools allow us to understand how individuals with various degrees of specialisation and ability end up together in certain industries and firms, giving place to various degrees of firm productivity. Our models can be easily used with standard labour force surveys and provide a framework to assess the impact skill complementarities in productivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Health Inequalities</title>
      <link>http://turingcss.org/projects/health_equity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://turingcss.org/projects/health_equity/</guid>
      <description>Project description Improving population health and reducing inequity is a critical issue that requires systemic interventions. All around the world, declines in life expectancy, widening inequalities in health, food and fuel insecurity, climate change, and restricted government budgets compound to make public health one of the greatest challenges that policymakers must face. As a systemic problem, public health cannot be tackled in isolation from other policy dimensions; hence, a holistic approach across public policy areas towards achieving good health outcomes for all is required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
